<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Junior Silva</title>
	<atom:link href="/https://juniorsilva1998.github.io/JuniorSilvaWebsiteGHPages/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/https://juniorsilva1998.github.io/JuniorSilvaWebsiteGHPages</link>
	<description>Learn more about Junior Silva and his accomplishments.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 21:49:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Opened up this website</title>
		<link>/https://juniorsilva1998.github.io/JuniorSilvaWebsiteGHPages/2023/05/09/hello-world/</link>
					<comments>/https://juniorsilva1998.github.io/JuniorSilvaWebsiteGHPages/2023/05/09/hello-world/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[juniorsilva3284]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 20:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/https://juniorsilva1998.github.io/JuniorSilvaWebsiteGHPages/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is my first post to say that this website is officially opened! While this is my first time setting up a website using WordPress, this isn&#8217;t exactly my first experience using WordPress. Back in September 2022, I have tried to make a local website using WordPress, but I had some difficulty installing it. I [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This is my first post to say that this website is officially opened!</p>



<p>While this is my first time setting up a website using WordPress, this isn&#8217;t exactly my first experience using WordPress. Back in September 2022, I have tried to make a local website using WordPress, but I had some difficulty installing it. I did play around with the website locally, but in the end, I didn&#8217;t have the motivation to continue. Now, my motivation has been resparked and I am willing to start this website.</p>



<p>For anyone trying to set one up for local use, I have some tips to make the whole thing easier.</p>



<p>The way I set up WordPress is to download XAMPP, which should include the latest version of PHP. It should support Windows, Linux, and MacOS. You can use this following link which leads to Apache Friends: <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://www.apachefriends.org/index.html" target="_blank">https://www.apachefriends.org/index.html</a>.</p>



<p>After downloading the installer, run the installer, and when you get to the screen where you install components, you want to make sure MySQL and phpMyAdmin are ticked. Click next, and it will ask you where to install XAMPP. I personally left the installation location as-is.</p>



<p>After the installation is complete, you can open the XAMPP Control Panel. Start Apache and MySQL. If they both are highlighted green, and you go to <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="http://localhost/" target="_blank">http://localhost/</a> on your favorite web browser and are able to see the XAMPP page, then congrats! That means everything is working as it should be.</p>



<p>Now for WordPress. Go to the WordPress.<strong>org</strong> website (not WordPress.<strong>com</strong>): <a rel="noreferrer noopener" href="https://wordpress.org/" target="_blank">https://wordpress.org/</a>. Download the latest version, and it should be a zip folder. Now extract it to where you installed XAMPP and extract the &#8220;wordpress&#8221; folder to the &#8220;htdocs&#8221; folder. By default, it should be C:\xampp\htdocs. After that, name the &#8220;wordpress&#8221; folder anything you&#8217;d like. It can be &#8220;testsite&#8221;, your name, etc.</p>



<p>Now you want to create a database for WordPress. To do that, you want to go to the XAMPP Control Panel, and click on Admin on the MySQL section, and it should show the webpage for phpMyAdmin. Go to the Databases tab and create a new database. Name it exactly what you named the &#8220;wordpress&#8221; folder. For example, if you renamed it as &#8220;testsite,&#8221; name the database &#8220;testsite.&#8221;</p>



<p>Now to actually install WordPress. On your web browser, type in http://localhost/(insert name of your &#8220;wordpress&#8221; folder). The webpage should come up as the WordPress installer. Select whatever language. Then enter Database Name (which should be whatever you entered in phpMyAdmin), Username (should be &#8220;root&#8221;), and Password (you can leave it blank). Leave Database host and Table Prefix as-is. After that, you can set up WordPress however you wanted to.</p>



<p>Some things I recommend when you actually open WordPress; you want to go to Settings, and change your WordPress address and Site Address to use &#8220;https&#8221; instead of &#8220;http.&#8221; This is because HTTPS is a lot more secure than HTTP, and the overwhelming majority of websites nowadays use HTTPS (over 95% to be exact). Also, go to php.ini, and go to the lines where you see &#8220;;extension=gd,&#8221; &#8220;;extension=intl,&#8221; and &#8220;;extension=zip.&#8221; Uncomment them by removing the semi-colon at the front, and save the file. This is because these modules are meant to be enabled for WordPress, but for some reason they were disabled when you install XAMPP.</p>



<p>Now have fun with WordPress.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/https://juniorsilva1998.github.io/JuniorSilvaWebsiteGHPages/2023/05/09/hello-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
